{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King","incorrectAnswers":["Lost in Translation","Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World","Mystic River"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2003?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"24","incorrectAnswers":["6","12","15"],"question":"How many ribs do most humans have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The flight deck","incorrectAnswers":["The hangar","The landing strip","The bridge"],"question":"What is the name of the place on aircraft carriers where the planes take off and land?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Winter's Tale'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sino-Tibetan","incorrectAnswers":["Japonic","Uralic","Kra–Dai"],"question":"The language 'Hakka' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the studio album 'All That You Can't Leave Behind'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American music duo released the song 'The Sound of Silence'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Crimean War","incorrectAnswers":["World War I","World War II","Russian Civil War"],"question":"The charge of the light brigade occured during which war?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Greece","The USA","Britain"],"question":"In which country was natural gas first used as a source of energy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Czech Republic","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","Slovenia","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Germany?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Athletics","Figure skating","Golf"],"question":"With which sport is Fred Perry associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Austroasiatic","Afroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Ukrainian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Being There","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","Pirates of the Caribbean","Wall Street"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Chance the Gardener'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Kuwait is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Werner Heisenberg","incorrectAnswers":["Enrico Fermi","Albert Einstein","Robert Oppenheimer"],"question":"Who Is Best Known For The Uncertainty Principle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics","incorrectAnswers":["Socialization, Teamwork, Empathy, and Memories","Sports, Teamwork, Endurance, and Motivation","Solutions, Technology, Education, and Management"],"question":"I'm education , what does the acronym 'STEM' stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Fort Knox","incorrectAnswers":["Fort Box","Fort Dox","Fort Stox"],"question":"Where is most of America's gold located?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lordi","incorrectAnswers":["Nightwish","Poets of the Fall","Stratovarius"],"question":"Which Finnish hard rock band released the album 'Get Heavy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Detroit Lions","incorrectAnswers":["Detroit Celtics","Detroit Giants","Detroit Steelers"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Detroit?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Champignon","incorrectAnswers":["Truffel","Oeuf","Baguette"],"question":"What is the French word for an edible mushroom?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Central America","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","The Middle East","South America"],"question":"From which part of the world does papaya originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"An Eyas","incorrectAnswers":["A Nymph","A Calf","A Poult"],"question":"What is a baby hawk known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Greece","Slovenia"],"question":"In which country is the Southernmost point of continental Europe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ligaments","incorrectAnswers":["Things which cannot be known","Butterflies and moths","Ants"],"question":"What is desmology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lonesome Dove","incorrectAnswers":["In Our Time","The Moviegoer","The Swimmer"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Augustus McCrae'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cricket","incorrectAnswers":["Motor Racing","Snooker","Rowing"],"question":"With which sport is Brian Lara associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"gemstones and ornamental materials","incorrectAnswers":["wood","one of two main branches of soil science","the nose and its diseases"],"question":"What is Gemmology or Gemology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Queen Alexandra's Birdwing","incorrectAnswers":["Emperor","Morpho","Gossamer-winged"],"question":"Which is the largest known butterfly?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jericho","incorrectAnswers":["Bagdhad","Rome","Damascus"],"question":"Which is the most ancient walled city?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Søren Kierkegaard","incorrectAnswers":["Ludwig Wittgenstein","Friedrich Nietzsche","Bertrand Russell"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Life must be understood backward. But it must be lived forward '?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Arendelle","incorrectAnswers":["Aldovia","Neuschwanstein","Llorien"],"question":"What is the name of the magical kingdom in Frozen?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lima","incorrectAnswers":["Praia","Caracas","Castries"],"question":"What is the capital city of Peru?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1997","incorrectAnswers":["1990","1982","1976"],"question":"In what year did the UK's lease on Hong Kong expire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Marvel","incorrectAnswers":["Wonder","DC","Image"],"question":"What is the name of the comic book company whose comics feature Spiderman?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Midway","incorrectAnswers":["Iwo Jima","Pearl Harbour","Okinawa"],"question":"In which WWII battle were four Japanese carriers destroyed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"study of human characteristics","incorrectAnswers":["the eyes","wood","the study and psychology of organisms with regard to their functions and structures"],"question":"What is Somatology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"96 Tears","incorrectAnswers":["Puttin' on the Ritz","Mambo No. 5 (A Little Bit Of...)","I'Ve Never Been to Me"],"question":"What song did ? & The Mysterians have a hit with in 1966?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Catholicism","incorrectAnswers":["Judaism","Protestantism","Paganism"],"question":"What religion was practiced by the Holy Roman Empire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Memento vivere","incorrectAnswers":["Vincit qui patitur","Palma non sine pulvere","Pro bono"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases translates to 'Remember to live'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"High Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Mannerism","Italian Renaissance","Surrealism"],"question":"The painting \"School of Athens\" by Raphael is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Winston Churchill","incorrectAnswers":["Abraham Lincoln","Neil Armstrong","Tom Cruise"],"question":"Who said 'I have nothing to offer but blood, tears, toil and sweat'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Christchurch","incorrectAnswers":["Hobart","Ballarat","Bendigo"],"question":"Which of these cities is in New Zealand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Nasi Goreng","incorrectAnswers":["Kabuli Pulao","Gallo Pinto","Crêpe"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Indonesia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Stella! Hey, Stella!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I see dead people.\"","\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\"","\"Toga! Toga!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'A Streetcar Named Desire'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Scotland","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Hungary","Thailand"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Haggis?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jonah Hill","incorrectAnswers":["Javier Bardem","Hugo Weaving","Warwick Davis"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Wolf of Wall Street and Moneyball?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Pen","incorrectAnswers":["A Jill","A Ewe","A Vixen"],"question":"A female swan is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"-40","incorrectAnswers":["0","16","64"],"question":"At Which Point Are The Temperature Scales Fahrenheit & Celcius The Same?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Vishnu","incorrectAnswers":["Brahma","Brihaspati","Krishna"],"question":"What is the name of the Hindu god of preservation?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'It'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"St. Peter","incorrectAnswers":["Jesus","The Angel Gabriel","Judas"],"question":"In biblical art, who is often depicted holding a key?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1980","incorrectAnswers":["1965","1970","1975"],"question":"Raging Bull was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Charles Guiteau","incorrectAnswers":["Charlotte Corday","John Wilkes Booth","Gavrilo Princip"],"question":"Who shot President James Garfield?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hippocrates","incorrectAnswers":["Leonidas","Euclid","Archimedes"],"question":"Who Is Known As The Father Of Medicine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"New Zealand","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","Ireland","Canada"],"question":"In which country is the city of Auckland?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bee Gees","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Culture Club","Dire Straits"],"question":"Which English-Australian pop group released the song 'To Love Somebody'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"H. G. Wells","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","Arthur C. Clarke","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Invisible Man'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"St. Augustine","incorrectAnswers":["St. Julius","St. May","St. Decembrius"],"question":"Which influential historical person was an influential Christian saint and writer, who shaped much of Western Christian thought?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I'm as mad as hell, and I'm not going to take this anymore!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"That is so fetch.\"","\"I love the smell of napalm in the morning.\"","\"E.T. phone home.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Network'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Slovakia","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Israel","Estonia"],"question":"Bratislava is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kurt Cobain","incorrectAnswers":["Dave Grohl","Eddie Vedder","Chris Cornell"],"question":"Who was the lead singer of the '90s rock band, Nirvana?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["China","South Korea","Vietnam"],"question":"What country is Haru-Urara, a racehorse that has lost over 100 races, from?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Igne natura renovatur integra","incorrectAnswers":["Nil volentibus arduum","Suum cuique","Praesis ut prosis ne ut imperes"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'Through fire, nature is reborn whole'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, actress and record producer released the studio album '4'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American singer and songwriter released the studio album 'Erotica'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tim Roth","incorrectAnswers":["Paul Newman","Tobey Maguire","Elijah Wood"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in both Twin Peaks and Pulp Fiction?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Yellow","incorrectAnswers":["Ten","Seven","Green"],"question":"In Portuguese, what is the meaning of the word 'amarelo'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Valkyrie","incorrectAnswers":["Jane Foster","Agent Peggy Carter","Thena"],"question":"Tessa Thompson plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Blót","incorrectAnswers":["Flägen","Midsommar","Odinskón"],"question":"What is the name of the Viking practice of sacrificing prisoners to their gods?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mosque","incorrectAnswers":["Church","Synagogue","Temple"],"question":"What is the name of the Islamic place of worship?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gabriel García Márquez","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","Søren Kierkegaard","Voltaire"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Love in the Time of Cholera'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Golden Horde","incorrectAnswers":["The Silver Horde","The Bronze Horde","The Copper Horde"],"question":"Which group emerged after the disintegration of the Mongol Empire and pillaged much of Europe throughout the 14th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Who prevails with God","incorrectAnswers":["God is my judge","God strengthens","God is with us"],"question":"What is the meaning of the name \"Israel\" in the Bible?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jane Austen","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley","Stephenie Meyer","Robert Louis Stevenson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Persuasion'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Portnoy's Complaint","incorrectAnswers":["One Hundred Years of Solitude","Heart of Darkness","The Big Sleep"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Alex Portnoy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Michael Keaton","incorrectAnswers":["Simon Pegg","Toshirō Mifune","Roger Moore"],"question":"Which actor has featured in both Spider-Man: Homecoming and Batman (1989)?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Shiva, Vishnu, and Brahma","incorrectAnswers":["Krishna, Rama, and Ganesha","Kali, Durga, and Saraswati","Indra, Agni, and Varuna"],"question":"Which three gods make up the Hindu Trimurti?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'Somebody to Love'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Raphael","incorrectAnswers":["Gustav Klimt","Eugène Delacroix","Henri Rousseau"],"question":"Which artist painted \"School of Athens\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Persephone","incorrectAnswers":["Artemis","Hera","Demeter"],"question":"Who was the Greek goddess of spring?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red with a blue cross outlined in white.","incorrectAnswers":["Three equal vertical bands of green, yellow, and red.","Red with a yellow sun having eight broadening rays extending to the edges.","White with a red and blue yin yang symbol in the center."],"question":"What does the flag of Norway look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Germany","United States"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1982 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Thirty Seconds to Mars","incorrectAnswers":["Green Day","Red Hot Chili Peppers","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which band is Jared Leto the lead singer for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Colossus","incorrectAnswers":["The Zeus","The Lighthouse","The Mausoleum"],"question":"What wonder stood 32m high in Rhodes harbour?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dutch East India Company","incorrectAnswers":["British East India Company","Portuguese East India Company","French East India Company"],"question":"In 1610, what firm shipped tea to Europe for the first time?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Self-Raising Flour ","incorrectAnswers":["Artificial Sweetener","Decaffeinated Coffee","Taurine"],"question":"What was discovered by the McDougall Brothers in 1864 after an experiment with phosphatic yeast?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Parthenon","incorrectAnswers":["The Colosseum","The Eiffel Tower","The Great Wall"],"question":"Which famous landmark has a full scale replica in Nashville, Tennessee?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The sewing machine","incorrectAnswers":["The washing machine","The dishwasher","The refrigerator"],"question":"Which invention was patented by both Isaac Singer and Elias Howe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Little Women","incorrectAnswers":["Buddenbrooks","David Copperfield","Jane Eyre"],"question":"In which book does 'Mr. March' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Michelangelo","incorrectAnswers":["Edvard Much","Leonardo da Vinci","Monet"],"question":"Who painted \"The Creation Of Adam\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Rugby","Baseball","Golf"],"question":"With which sport do you associate `Flushing Meadows`?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Timor-Leste","incorrectAnswers":["Grenada","Kuwait","Romania"],"question":"Dili is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Citizen Kane","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","Gone with the Wind","Casablanca"],"question":"What is the name of the 1941 film that topped the AFI's  1998 list of the 100 greatest American films?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Uni ","incorrectAnswers":["Oni","Ani","Eni"],"question":"Sea Urchin Sushi Is Known As What In Japanese?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Agitate","incorrectAnswers":["Oscillate","Vibrate","Tremble"],"question":"In laboratory settings, what word is used to refer to the act of stirring or shaking a liquid?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mustang","incorrectAnswers":["Smirnoff","ING Group","Swarovski"],"question":"Which of these brands has a horse on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Betamax","incorrectAnswers":["VHS","SuperMotion","Videoman"],"question":"What was the name of the domestic videocassette tape recorder system introduced by Sony in 1975?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Flower","incorrectAnswers":["Root","Leaf","Seed"],"question":"What part of the kudzu plant can be turned into a jelly?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Thomas Mann","incorrectAnswers":["F. Scott Fitzgerald","Philip K. Dick","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Joseph and His Brothers'?","difficulty":"hard"},